Guide to the Ian P. Watt Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ian P. Watt papers
1956-1989
SC0401
Watt, Ian P.
55 Linear feet
Correspondence, lectures, notes, course materials, bibliographies, articles, proofs, clippings, and reprints pertaining to courses he taught, departmental business, academic associations, and other professional activities. Some of the material pertains to his teaching at UC Berkeley before he came to Stanford; also included are materials pertaining to his experiences as a Japanese prisoner of war during World War II and the building of the bridge over the River Kwai.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Preliminary inventory available.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Watt earned his degrees at Cambridge and taught there and at UC Berkeley before joining the Stanford faculty in 1964 as Professor of English. In 1971 he was named Jackson Eli Reynolds professor of the humanities and was the first director of the Stanford Humanities Center.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, lectures, notes, course materials, bibliographies, articles, proofs, clippings, and reprints pertaining to courses he taught, departmental business, academic associations, and other professional activities. Some of the material pertains to his teaching at UC Berkeley before he came to Stanford; also included are materials pertaining to his experiences as a Japanese prisoner of war during World War II and the building of the bridge over the River Kwai.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of English.; Stanford University. Humanities Center.; Watt, Ian P.; English literature--Study and teaching.; World War, 1939-1945--Prisoners and prisons, Japanese.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1990-131
  - "A" (Box 1)
  - ACLS (Box 1)
  - ACLS: 1965 (+1961) (Box 1)
  - ACLS (Correspondence) (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Curriculum (Box 1)
  - Alabama: Joyce and Yeats (Box 1)
  - Albert, Theodore (Box 1)
  - Alden, Patricia (Box 1)
  - Alfaro, Christine (Box 1)
  - Almodovar, Carmen (Box 1)
  - Altieri, Charles (University of Washington) (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts Sciences (Box 1)
  - AAAL - Selection Committee (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Committee (Box 1)
  - Ames, Christopher (Box 1)
  - Ames, Dianne (Box 1)
  - Ames, Michael (Box 1)
  - ASECS: Correspondence, Bulletin (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Howard (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Judith (Box 2)
  - Animals (Box 2)
  - Anon (Box 2)
  - Antin, David (Box 2)
  - Antonides, Jill (Box 2)
  - Anxiety (Box 2)
  - Arendt, Hannah (Box 2)
  - Armstron, James (Box 2)
  - Art (Box 2)
  - Asbridge, N. S. 1975 (Box 2)
  - Auerbach (Box 2)
  - August, Paul Nordstrom (Box 2)
  - 18th Century Bibliography of Augustanism (Box 2)
  - Augustan Anthology: Notes for Introduction (Box 2)
  - Augustanism: BBC (Correspondence, Talks) (Box 2)
  - Augustanism: Current (Box 2)
  - Augustan Attittudes: Plans (Box 2)
  - Augustanism: BBC (Notes) (Box 2)
  - Jane Austen:
    - Research Correspondence Offprints (Box 2)
    - Pre-Washington (Box 2)
    - Comedy of Control (Box 2)
    - '77 - Washington Version (Box 2)
    - Latest Version - Master (Box 2)
    - Current Annotation (Box 2)
    - Notes (1) (Box 3)
    - Notes (2) (Box 3)
    - English 185B (Box 3)
  - Australia Plans (Box 3)
  - Australian National University - Research Center (Box 3)
  - "B" - Correspondence (1) (Box 3)
  - "B" - Correspondence (2) (Box 3)
  - Backus, Jjoe (Box 3)
  - Baines (Box 3)
  - Balzac (Box 3)
  - Baridon, Michel (Box 3)
  - Barthes (Box 3)
  - Basker (Box 3)
  - Bateman, Lewis (Box 3)
  - Battenfield, David (Box 3)
  - Batchelor, John (Box 3)
  - Bateson (Box 3)
  - Baudelaire (Box 4)
  - Baumgarten, Murray (Box 4)
  - Baxter, WM. (Box 4)
  - Baycroft, Bernard (Box 4)
  - Beasley (Smollet Edition) (Box 4)
  - Bedell, Jeanne (Box 4)
  - Begley, Adam (Box 4)
  - Bellhouse, Mary (Box 4)
  - Bellow (Box 4)
  - Bender (Box 4)
  - Bender, Todd (Box 4)
  - Bensen (Box 4)
  - Bergeron, A. W. (Box 4)
  - Berlot, John (Box 4)
  - Berman (Box 4)
  - Berryman, John (Box 4)
  - Bertrand, Marc (Box 4)
  - Bier, Jesse (Box 4)
  - Binni, Francesco (Box 4)
  - Bimber, Bruce (Box 4)
  - Birmingham (Box 4)
  - Blake (Box 4)
  - Blair, Sara (Box 4)
  - Blau, Robert (Box 4)
  - Blewett, David (Box 4)
  - Blewett (18th Century Fiction) (Box 4)
  - Bliss, Richard (Box 4)
  - Bloom, Allan (Box 4)
  - Blumberd, Barry (Box 4)
  - Bobb-Merrill 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bobb-Merrill: Editorial Handouts (Box 5)
  - Bobb-Merril:l Revised Shakespeare Instructions (Box 5)
  - Boebel, C. (Box 5)
  - Bohls, Liz (Box 5)
  - (The) Book (Box 5)
  - Bookstore (Box 5)
  - Boredom (Box 5)
  - Borges, Luis (Box 5)
  - Bossert, Rex (Box 5)
  - Bowen, Zach (Box 5)
  - Boxer, Susan (Box 5)
  - Brady, Frank (Box 5)
  - Bradshaw (Box 5)
  - Bratman (Box 5)
  - Brattin (Box 5)
  - Braudel (Box 5)
  - Brecht (Box 5)
  - Breckinridge (Box 5)
  - Brever (Box 5)
  - Bridgman (Box 5)
  - BBC (Box 5)
  - BBC (Box 5)
  - British Council (Box 5)
  - Bromell (Box 6)
  - Bronte, E. - Wuthering Heights (Box 6)
  - Brooke, Nicholas (Box 6)
  - Brooks, Peter (Box 6)
  - Bross (Box 6)
  - Brown, Bill (Box 6)
  - Bruhn, Karin (Box 6)
  - Bureacracy (Box 6)
  - Burke (Studies his times) (Box 6)
  - Burney (Box 6)
  - Burns, Margie (Box 6)
  - Butt (Box 6)
  - Butte, George (Box 6)
  - Byrd, Max (Box 6)
  - "C" 1 (Box 6)
  - "C" 2 (Box 6)
  - Cahill (Box 6)
  - Cambridge Univ. (Debate) (Box 6)
  - Cambridge Univ.: American Friends (Box 6)
  - Campbell, Wm. (Box 6)
  - Canada: Council (Box 6)
  - Campus Conference (Box 6)
  - Canetti, Elias (Box 6)
  - Cantrell, Carol (Box 6)
  - Cardan, Jerome (Box 6)
  - Carolan, James (Box 6)
  - Carr, Arthur (Box 7)
  - Carroll (Box 7)
  - Carron, Tom (Box 7)
  - Cartwright, Richard (Box 7)
  - Carver, Anthony (Box 7)
  - Cash, Arthur (Box 7)
  - Castenada, Marina (Box 7)
  - Cauanagh (Box 7)
  - Casba - Adv. Comm. Meeting 1984 1985 (Box 7)
  - Cavel, S. (Box 7)
  - Cebula (Box 7)
  - Center (Box 7)
  - Center: 1976- 1977 (Box 7)
  - Center: Current (Box 7)
  - Chang, Maida (Box 7)
  - Chase, Karen (Box 7)
  - Chow, Rey (Box 7)
  - Chill, Robert (Box 7)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 7)
  - Christmas (Box 7)
  - Cir. - Current (Box 8)
  - Clark, Judith (Box 8)
  - Clark Library Lecture Series (UCLA) (Box 8)
  - Clarke, Colin (Box 8)
  - Clifford, James (UC Santa Cruz) (Box 8)
  - Clint, Wilson (Box 8)
  - Close, J. B. (Box 8)
  - Coast, John (Box 8)
  - Coers, Donald (Box 8)
  - Cohen, Ed (Box 8)
  - Coleman, Bob (Box 8)
  - Coleridge (Box 8)
  - College: English (Box 8)
  - Colliers (Box 8)
  - Collins, Arthur (Box 8)
  - Collins, Philip A. W. (Box 8)
  - Collins, Wilke (Box 8)
  - Colorado, Univ. of (Box 8)
  - Columbia Univ. Press (Box 8)
  - Columbia Reports (Box 8)
  - Comedy (Box 8)
  - Comedy: Project (Box 8)
  - Comer, Barbara (Box 8)
  - Commencement (Box 8)
  - Communications, Encyclopedia of (Box 8)
  - Computer (Box 8)
  - Conger, S. M. (Box 8)
  - Conrad:
    - Exams (Box 8)
    - Heart of Darkness Berkeley 203Q (Box 8)
    - 277 (Box 8)
    - Conrad (Box 8)
    - Conrad Seminar (Box 8)
    - 277 - Fall 1984 Lectures (Box 8)
    - Course Folder 277 (Box 9)
    - Seminar 1987 (Box 9)
    - 288F - Fall 1978 (Box 9)
    - 395 - 1983 Conrad (Box 9)
    - Conrad Ad Hoc Seminar 395 (Box 9)
    - Glossary - Nostrome Aids (Box 9)
    - Course Handouts (Box 9)
    - Course Handouts (Box 9)
    - Southern Review (Box 9)
    - Conrad Society (Box 9)
    - NEH (Michael) (Box 9)
    - NEH (Harkness) (Box 9)
    - NEH (Dalgarno) (Box 9)
  - Commission on Investment Responsibility (Looseleaf folder) (Box 9)
  - Cook, Elizabeth (Box 9)
  - Cornell (Watt) (Box 9)
  - Covolo, John (Box 9)
  - Cozad, Mary Lee (Box 9)
  - Critical Inquiry (Box 9)
  - Critical Quarterly (Box 9)
  - Criticism (Box 9)
  - Crolius, Stephen (Box 9)
  - Culler, Jonathan (Box 9)
  - Curreli (Box 9)
  - Curtis Brown (Box 10)
  - Curry, George (Box 10)
  - Cushing, John (re. Gary Goodman) (Box 10)
  - C. Cusie (Box 10)
  - Daleski, Bill (Box 10)
  - Davies, John (Box 10)
  - Davis, Charles (Box 10)
  - Davis, Elizabeth (Box 10)
  - Davis, Gabriele (Box 10)
  - Davis, Jane (Box 10)
  - Davison, Peter (Box 10)
  - Daws, Gavin (Box 10)
  - de Angelis, Umberto (Box 10)
  - De Gaulle (Box 10)
  - Deconstruction (Box 10)
  - De Guigne (Box 10)
  - Dekker, George (Box 10)
  - Dent (Box 10)
  - Derivation (Box 10)
  - Derrida (Box 10)
  - Dickason - Orals (Box 10)
  - Dickens Society (Box 10)
  - Dickens (Box 10)
  - Dickens Prize (Box 10)
  - Dickens Conference (Box 11)
  - Dickey, John (Box 11)
  - Dickey, Lew (Box 11)
  - Dictionaries (Box 11)
  - Dijkstra (Box 11)
  - Mimesis Morphogenesis 1983 (Box 11)
  - Dolin, Sharon (Box 11)
  - Dostoevsky (Box 11)
  - Dowling (Box 11)
  - Duke Univ. (Box 11)
  - Dunn, Richard (Box 11)
  - Eagleton, Terry (Box 11)
  - Easter (Box 11)
  - Eco, Umberto (Box 11)
  - Edwards, Mark (Box 11)
  - 18th Century:
    - Letters (Box 11)
    - Studies (Box 11)
    - Fiction (Box 11)
  - Eggers, J. Philip (Box 11)
  - Eleasari, Rava (Box 11)
  - Eliot, T.S. (Box 11)
  - Ellison, David (Box 11)
  - Ellmann, Richard (Box 11)
  - Emerson, Betty (Box 11)
  - Emery, Mary Lou (Box 11)
  - Emprisonment (Box 11)
  - Empon (Box 11)
  - Enccyclopedia of Communication (Box 11)
  - English Institute (Box 11)
  - Etlinger Talk 1979 (Box 11)
  - "F" (Box 11)
  - Faculty Club (Box 11)
  - Faculty Seminars (American Studies 1983 - 1984) (Box 11)
  - Faculty Seminars (American Studies 1983 - 1984) (Box 11)
  - Faulkner (Box 11)
  - Fawcett Anthology (Box 11)
  - Fawcett: Augustan Age (Box 11)
  - Felstiner, John (Box 12)
  - Fetter, Jean (Box 12)
  - Fiedler, Leslie (Box 12)
  - Fielding (Box 12)
  - Fish, Stanley (Box 12)
  - Flanagan, Mary (Box 12)
  - Flaubert (Box 12)
  - Flegs, Fabio (Box 12)
  - Fleigelman, Jay (Box 12)
  - Folkenflik (Box 12)
  - Follesdal, Dagfrim (Box 12)
  - Fontana, Ernest (Box 12)
  - Foster (Box 12)
  - Foster: Neitzsche (Box 12)
  - Foucault, Michel (Box 12)
  - Fox, Christopher (Box 12)
  - France (Box 12)
  - Franks, Ellen (Box 12)
  - Frazier, Harriet (Box 12)
  - Freccers (Box 12)
  - Fredman, Stephen (Box 12)
  - Freiman (Box 12)
  - Frelis (Box 12)
  - Friedlander, Carl (Box 12)
  - Friedlander, Carl (Box 12)
  - Frye, Northrop (Box 12)
  - Furst, L. (Box 12)
  - Fussell, Paul (Box 12)
  - Gibian, Peter (Box 12)
  - Gifford, Dan (Box 12)
  - Gilbert (Box 12)
  - Gilfond (Box 12)
  - Gilman, Stephen (Box 12)
  - Girsh - MLA (Box 12)
  - Glenn, Ian (Box 12)
  - Goff, Sean C. (Box 13)
  - Goldman (Box 13)
  - Goodman, Gary Sue (Box 13)
  - Gorra (Box 13)
  - Gothic:
    - Virginia Earlier Versions (Box 13)
    - Texas, Scott (Box 13)
    - Other Essays (Box 13)
    - Paper (Box 13)
  - Gothic (Box 13)
  - Grabowski, Douglas (Box 13)
  - Graham, Mark Phillip (Box 13)
  - Graver, Suzanne (Box 13)
  - Graver, Larry (Box 13)
  - Gray, Thomas (Box 13)
  - Gray - Balle (Box 13)
  - Greenberg, J. (Box 13)
  - Grice Paper (Box 13)
  - Griswold, Wendy (Box 13)
  - Grossman, Richard (Box 13)
  - Guggenheims, -Mine (Box 14)
  - Guggenheims: -Nominations (Box 14)
  - Habbakuk article (Box 14)
  - Habegger (Box 14)
  - Habermass (Box 14)
  - Hagstrum (Box 14)
  - Halliburton (Box 14)
  - Halperin, John (Box 14)
  - Handouts:
    - Auden (Box 14)
    - Character (Box 14)
    - Chaucer - Language (Box 14)
    - Chronology (Box 14)
    - Conrad Cay (Box 14)
    - Cuckoo (Box 14)
    - Death (Box 14)
    - 18th Cent. Fiction (Box 14)
    - Eloit (Box 14)
    - Empson (Box 14)
    - Fielding Woolf (Box 14)
    - Greens (Box 14)
    - Heart of Darkness (Box 14)
    - Irony (Box 14)
    - Jonson Ransom (Box 14)
    - Leavis (Box 14)
    - Lovejoy - "Nature" (Box 14)
    - Meredith Forster (Box 14)
    - Narrative Style (Box 14)
    - Plagiarism (Box 14)
    - Precis (Box 14)
    - Proclusions (Box 14)
    - Punctuation (Box 15)
    - MA - B Reading List (Box 15)
    - Dylan Thomas (Box 15)
    - Tristram Shandy (Box 15)
    - Ulysses (Box 15)
    - Vocabulary (Box 15)
    - Waller (Box 15)
    - Waste-Land Notes (Box 15)
  - Hardy (Box 15)
  - Harkness Fund (Box 15)
  - Harkness, Bruce (Box 15)
  - Harm, Roger L. (Box 15)
  - Harper (Box 15)
  - Harrington, Hank (Box 15)
  - Harris, Elizabeth (Box 15)
  - Harris, Jocelyn (Box 15)
  - Harris, Neil (Box 15)
  - Harrison, Tony (Box 15)
  - Hartman (Box 15)
  - Harvard Visit (Box 15)
  - Harvard Univ. (Box 15)
  - Harvard U.P. (Box 15)
  - Harvard U.P. (Box 15)
  - Harvey, Bruce - Orals (Box 15)
  - Hasbach, Corinna (Box 15)
  - Hunt - Hawkins (Box 15)
  - Hearle, Kevin (Box 16)
  - Hegel (Box 16)
  - Heidegger & the Nazis (Box 16)
  - Hellenbrand, harry (Box 16)
  - Heller, Erich (Box 16)
  - Hemingway (Box 16)
  - Henkle (Box 16)
  - Hess, Myra (Box 16)
  - Hessler (Box 16)
  - Hilton, Ronald (Box 16)
  - Hirsch, Don (Box 16)
  - Ho, Bruce (Box 16)
  - Hobbes (Box 16)
  - Hobsbawm, Eric (Box 16)
  - Hoff, Peter (Box 16)
  - Hogue, Lawrence (Box 16)
  - England: Homeland (Box 16)
  - Homosexuality (Box 16)
  - Honors Essays (Box 16)
  - Horowitz & Cohen Conf. (Box 16)
  - Horowitz, Helen (Box 16)
  - Horsman, Alan - Festschrift (Box 16)
  - Horton, Larry (Box 16)
  - Houston Travel (Box 16)
  - Hughes, Dean t. (Box 16)
  - Humanities Center (Box 16)
  - Humanities & Stanford 1984 (Box 17)
  - Humanities & Stanford: Provost's Series (Box 17)
  - Humanities & Stanford: Provost's Talk (Box 17)
  - Humanities & Stanford: Dictionary Entries (Box 17)
  - Humanities Institute (Box 17)
  - Humanities: Offprints (Box 17)
  - Humanities: Cuttings (Box 17)
  - U. C. Humanities (Box 17)
  - Humanities: Classical (Box 18)
  - Humour (Box 18)
  - Hunter, J. Paul (Box 18)
  - Hutchinson (Box 18)
  - Hutter, Albert (Box 18)
  - Huxley, Alduous (Box 18)
  - "I" (Box 18)
  - I.A.U.P.E.:
    - Aberdeen (Box 18)
    - Aberdeen (Box 18)
    - 1980 Other Correspondence (Box 18)
    - 1980 M. Kinkead - Weekes (Box 18)
    - Andrew Rutherford (Box 18)
    - Marren-Sophie Rostwig (Box 18)
    - George S. Rousseau (Box 18)
    - Conference 1986, York (Box 18)
  - I Tatti (Box 18)
  - Ibsen (Box 18)
  - Ideology (Box 18)
  - University of Illinois (Box 18)
  - Imagination (Box 18)
  - IMHOFI (Box 18)
  - Indiana: Teachning (Box 18)
  - Indiana: Visit (Box 18)
  - Indiana: Visit (Box 18)
  - Individualism (Box 18)
  - Irony (Box 18)
  - Isherwood (Box 18)
  - Ives, Charles (Box 18)
  - -J- (Box 18)
  - James, Henry (Box 18)
  - Jameson, Michael (Box 18)
  - Jefferson (Box 18)
  - Johnson, Lee (Box 19)
  - Johnson, Samuel (Box 19)
  - Johnson, Sidney (Box 19)
  - Joplin, Patti (Box 19)
  - Josephs, Hilary (Box 19)
  - Joyce, James (Box 19)
  - Janker Man (Box 19)
  - -K- (Box 19)
  - Kaiser, Lawrence (Box 19)
  - University of Kansas (Box 19)
  - Katrutzky, Linda (Box 19)
  - Kay, Carol (Box 19)
  - Kaye, Roger (Box 19)
  - Kazin, Alfred (Box 19)
  - Keats (Box 19)
  - Keith, Frank (Box 19)
  - Kelley, Wyn (Box 19)
  - Kennedy, Jeanne (Box 19)
  - Kerman (Box 19)
  - Kermode, Frank (Box 19)
  - Kershner (Box 19)
  - Pynchon Heller Kesey (Bibliography) (Box 19)
  - Kettle, Arnold (Box 19)
  - Keynes (Box 19)
  - Kiely (Box 19)
  - Keirkegaard, Soren (Box 20)
  - Kimball, R. (Box 20)
  - Kimborough (Box 20)
  - Kipling (Box 20)
  - Kirshner (Box 20)
  - Kirsten, Terry (Box 20)
  - Kitchin, Laurence (Box 20)
  - Klages, Mary K. (Box 20)
  - Kline Paper (Box 20)
  - Kolve, Del (Box 20)
  - Konigsberg (Box 20)
  - Kortum, Karl (Box 20)
  - Kozloff, Sarah (Box 20)
  - Kramer (Box 20)
  - Kundera, Milan (Box 20)
  - Kotchea, Sister (Box 20)
  - Lacan (Box 20)
  - Larkin (Box 20)
  - Lashof (Box 20)
  - Lawrence (Box 20)
  - Laycock (Box 20)
  - Lazere, Donald (Box 20)
  - Leitch Reporst (Box 20)
  - IL -- Hwain Lee (Box 20)
  - IL -- Hwain Lee (Box 20)
  - Levenson (Box 20)
  - Lever, Karen M. (Box 20)
  - Levi-Strauss (Box 20)
  - Levin, David (Box 20)
  - Levin, Richard (Box 21)
  - Levine, George (Box 21)
  - Levy (Box 21)
  - Levy (Box 21)
  - Stanford University Library -- SHC (Box 21)
  - Lindenberger, H. (Box 21)
  - Literacy Talk -- Materials (Box 21)
  - Literacy: Lazere (Box 21)
  - Literacy Prizes (Box 21)
  - Literature (Box 21)
  - Loewenstein, Joseph (Box 21)
  - Long, David (Box 21)
  - Long, Chip (Box 21)
  - Lopez-Aquada (Box 21)
  - Loschen (Box 21)
  - Lothe, Jakob (Box 21)
  - Lougell, Carolyn (Box 21)
  - Loukides (Box 21)
  - Lowell, Robert (Box 21)
  - Lubbock - Visit (Box 21)
  - Lucas, George (Box 21)
  - Lukacs (Box 21)
  - Luftig, Victor (Box 21)
  - -M- (Box 21)
  - M #1 (Box 21)
  - M #2 (Box 22)
  - Mac Arthur Fellows (Box 22)
  - McCarthy, Mignon (Box 22)
  - McDonald, E. Milton (Box 22)
  - McGann (Box 22)
  - McGraw Hill Anthology (Box 22)
  - McGraw Hill Anthology (Box 22)
  - MacIntyre, Alasdein (Box 22)
  - McMasty, Juliet (Box 22)
  - McMaster (Box 22)
  - MacMillan (Box 22)
  - McLaughlin, Juliet [?] (Box 22)
  - McMullen (Box 22)
  - McMurtry, Larry (Box 22)
  - Mack (Box 22)
  - McKeon Review (Box 22)
  - McKeon, Michael (Box 22)
  - McNees, John (Box 22)
  - Mael, Phyllis (Box 22)
  - Magub (Box 22)
  - Marler, Norman (Box 22)
  - Malamud (Box 22)
  - Mann, Herbert (Box 22)
  - "Maris and the Magician" (Box 22)
  - Marlene (Box 23)
  - Marlowe (Box 23)
  - Marquez (Box 23)
  - Martin, Erin (Box 23)
  - Manz, Les (Box 23)
  - Marxism (Box 23)
  - Maves (Box 23)
  - Medina, Angel (Box 23)
  - Mellinkoff, Abe (Box 23)
  - Mellinkoff, Sherman (Box 23)
  - Mellon (Morris) (Box 23)
  - Menikoff, Barry (Box 23)
  - Methuen & Co., LTD (Box 23)
  - Michaels, Lemand (Box 23)
  - U of Michigan Press (Box 23)
  - Middlebrook Proposal (Box 23)
  - Millbauer (Box 23)
  - Millbauer (Box 23)
  - Miller, Eugene (Box 23)
  - Millar, John (Box 23)
  - Miller, James (Box 23)
  - Milosz - Poland 1980 (Box 23)
  - Mimesis Papers (Box 23)
  - Miner, Earl (Box 23)
  - Minnesota, Univ. of (Box 23)
  - Minnesota, Univ. of (Box 24)
  - Mintz (Box 24)
  - Missouri, U of (Box 24)
  - Missouri, U of: Kansas City (Box 24)
  - Missouri, U of: Review (Box 24)
  - Miyoshki (Box 24)
  - Le Moal (Box 24)
  - MLA Newsletter (Box 24)
  - PMLA Reading (Box 24)
  - MLA - research activities (Box 24)
  - MLA:
    - 1981 (NY) (Box 24)
    - 1984 (Box 24)
    - 1980 (Box 24)
    - Not Prose Fiction 1980 (Box 24)
    - 1977, 1978, 1979 (Box 24)
    - 1977 Biography Meeting (Box 24)
    - Expenses 1977 (Box 24)
    - MLA - research activities: 1972 (Box 24)
    - 1970 (Box 24)
    - Reports on MSS (Box 24)
    - 1965-68 Corr. and Travel (Box 24)
    - Paper 1966 (Box 24)
    - Prose Fiction Committee (Box 24)
    - Prose Fiction 1980 (Box 24)
  - Modernism (Box 24)
  - Modern Language Quarterly (Box 24)
  - Modleski, Tania (Box 24)
  - Moir (Box 24)
  - Moore, Gene (Box 24)
  - Morales (Box 24)
  - Morawa (Box 24)
  - Morse, Margaret (Box 24)
  - Morse, Richard M. (Box 24)
  - Moser, Tom Jr. (Box 24)
  - Moses, Lincoln (Box 25)
  - Moyer (Box 25)
  - Mroczowski, Przemyslaw (Box 25)
  - Muller, David (Box 25)
  - -N- (Box 25)
  - NEH:
    - Reunion Application (Box 25)
    - Fellowship (Box 25)
    - 1977 - List of Fellows (Box 25)
    - 1977 - Today's Class (Box 25)
    - 1977 - Budget (Box 25)
    - 1977 - Stanford Budget Negotiations (Box 25)
    - 1977 - Class Handouts (Box 25)
    - Accounts 1975 (Box 25)
    - Reports (Box 25)
    - Administration (Box 25)
    - 1979 (Box 25)
    - 1979 (Box 25)
    - Reports (Box 25)
    - Social Arrangements (Box 25)
    - Administration Current (Box 25)
    - General Notes (Box 25)
    - Classwork - Used (Box 25)
    - 1979 - Admissions (Box 25)
    - 1979 - Housing (Box 25)
    - 1979 - Housing (Box 26)
    - 1979 - Lists and Proformas (Box 26)
    - 1979 - Budget (Box 26)
    - 1979 - My Proformas (Box 26)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 26)
    - Johnson Edition (Box 26)
    - Fellowships (Box 26)
    - Seminar Directors 1983 (Box 26)
    - Research Grant (Box 26)
    - IPW (Box 26)
  - NHC: Early Planning (Box 26)
  - NHC: Correspondence (Box 26)
  - Nabakov (Box 26)
  - Namphy (Box 26)
  - Narrative (Box 26)
  - Nature (Box 26)
  - NCF (Box 26)
  - Nebraska, U of (Box 26)
  - Nettles, Elsa (Box 26)
  - Neugeboren, Jay (Box 26)
  - New - Recommendations (Box 26)
  - New: TS Edition (Box 27)
  - NY Times Book Review (Box 27)
  - Stanford Conference (Box 27)
  - Nice & Paris (Box 27)
  - Nietzsche (Box 27)
  - Nobel Prize for Literature (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, U of (Box 27)
  - Norton's (Box 27)
  - Norwich:
    - (Souvenirs) (Box 27)
    - Curriculum (Box 27)
    - Ses (Box 27)
    - Clippings (Box 27)
    - History (Box 27)
    - Lectures (Box 27)
  - Correspondence (Box 27)
  - Notre Dame (Box 27)
  - Novel (Box 27)
  - Nigger of Narcissus (Box 27)
  - Nostromo (Box 27)
  - Pink Toads (Box 27)
  - Preface to Nigger of Narcissus (Box 27)
  - Conrad Letters Review (Box 27)
  - Secret Agent (Box 27)
  - Shadow Line (Box 28)
  - Secret Sharer (Box 28)
  - Criticism (The Listener) (Box 28)
  - Penguin: Correspondence (Box 28)
  - Penguin: Ford Correspondence (Box 28)
  - Defoe: Penguin Revisions (Box 28)
  - Defoe: Penguin Revisions (Box 28)
  - Proofs: Penguin (Box 28)
  - Defoe (Box 28)
  - Dickens (Box 28)
  - Dickens:
    - Dickens: 1973 Version (Box 28)
    - Dickens: Annotation Final Copy (Box 29)
    - Dickens: Article - Correspondence (Box 29)
    - Dickens: Penultimate Draft (Box 29)
  - Oral Pleas. in Great Expectations (Box 29)
  - Oral in Martin Chuzzlewit (Box 29)
  - Oral Dickens: Notes not used (Box 29)
  - Dickens: Psychological Notes (Box 29)
  - Dover Article (Box 29)
  - Penguin 2: Revision (Box 29)
  - Penguin, Vol. 2 revisions (Box 29)
  - Penguin, Vol. 2 revisions (Box 29)
  - Elizabethan Fiction (Box 29)
  - Elizabethan Fiction (Box 29)
  - Elizabethan Fiction (Box 29)
  - Elizabethan Fiction (Box 29)
  - Elizabethan Fiction (Box 29)
  - Elizabethan Fiction (Box 30)
  - Glosses (Box 30)
  - Ironic Tradition with Notes (Box 30)
  - Irony (Box 30)
  - James (Box 30)
  - Ambassadors: Reviews & Correspondence (Box 30)
  - Joseph Andrews Introduction (Box 30)
  - Joseph Andrews (Box 30)
  - Kwai: Recent Correspondence (Box 30)
  - Current Kwai Myth, slide version (Box 30)
  - Bridges over the Kwai, photocopies of published articles from Partisan Review and The Listener, 1959 (Box 31)
  - Kwai: clippings, 1972-73; typescript "‘The Bridge over the River Kwai' as Political, Psychological and Social Myth"; French translation of typescript; and misc. notes (Box 31)
  - Kwai Myth: U.S. revision, typescript, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Kwai: version for Life with correspondence, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Life magazine, Oct. 1968 (Box 31)
  - Return to Kwai: Early Draft undated (Box 31)
  - Reunion on the Kwai: typescript "Return to the Kwai: Scenes and Reflections" and correspondence, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Reunion on the Kwai: as published in The Southern Review 1969 (Box 31)
  - Kwai: Reviews and Correspondence, 1956-73 (Box 31)
  - Liberty of the Prison: the article, 1958, and correspondence (including 1 fragment) 1954-57 (Box 31)
  - Literacy: "The Consequences of Literacy" by Watt and Jack Goody, 1963 and 1968 (Box 31)
  - "The Recent Critical Fortunes of Moll Flanders" E.C.S offprints and notes, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Moll Flanders: Fawcett Correspondence (Box 32)
  - Moll Flanders: Fawcett Correspondence (Box 32)
  - Naming of Characters (Box 32)
  - Junior E.B. Correspondence (Box 32)
  - 1984: Campus, NY Paper: Conference (Box 32)
  - 1984 Corr. paperback (Box 32)
  - Orwell: xeroxes (Box 32)